<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>DrosoCode</title><link>https://thomasz.me/</link><description>DrosoCode</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>contact@thomasz.me (droso)</managingEditor><webMaster>contact@thomasz.me (droso)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomasz.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create your own ambilight solution</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2022/05/30/create-you-own-ambilight-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2022/05/30/create-you-own-ambilight-solution/</guid><description>Ambilight is a technology of Bias lighting used in Phillips TVs which illumitates the back of your tv with colors related to the image displayed. Their solution is expensive, but you can create your own solution using an ESP 8266 controller and some cheap led strips.
In order to adapt the lights to the image, the ambilight system needs to capture the images displayed on your tv. There are 2 main ways to do that: you can use a physical box to capture the video using an HDMI splitter and an acquisition card between your devices (Mi Box, Nvidia Shield, Xbox &amp;hellip;) and your TV or you can use a software solution to directly stream the video from a device (PC, Android TV &amp;hellip;).</description></item><item><title>A comparison of upscaling software in 2021</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/a-comparison-of-upscaling-software-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/a-comparison-of-upscaling-software-in-2021/</guid><description>A few months ago, I started to search for some upscaling software to integrate into Zogwine, my media center with the goal of upscaling some of my old animes either on the fly or via some kind of preprocessing. I found quite a lot of projects on github, and especially the Video2X project which gathered many different projects and versions. So I decided to do a quick benchmark to decide which one to use.</description></item><item><title>Easily create you DIY IoT devices with ESP Home and Home Assistant</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/easily-create-you-diy-iot-devices-with-esp-home-and-home-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/easily-create-you-diy-iot-devices-with-esp-home-and-home-assistant/</guid><description>When I started to tinker with home automation and electronics a few years ago, it was common to use arduino cards to create DIY connected devices. You would then communicate with a central server to send and receive information. The communications were usually done using usb, ethernet (using an ethernet shield) or radio (2.4Ghz or 433Mhz) with projects like MySensors.
Most of the time these cards were programmed using the “Arduino language” which is quite close to C++.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading your RGB with WLED, Aurora and OpenRGB</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2021/11/29/upgrading-your-rgb-with-wled-aurora-and-openrgb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2021/11/29/upgrading-your-rgb-with-wled-aurora-and-openrgb/</guid><description>I was always interested in going furether than the pre-made RGB equipement by various manufacturers because each system was only compatible with only one brand (ex: iCUE, RGB Fusion, Asus RGB …) and that their RGB softwares were very unfinished and didn’t exploit the full potential of the RGB hardware.
First Attempt So, when I built my first desktop PC, I decided to create from scratch a custom RGB system. This was based on an arduino board, internally connected to my PC using USB.</description></item><item><title>Control your lights with a Nintendo DS</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2020/11/03/control-your-light-with-a-nintendo-ds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2020/11/03/control-your-light-with-a-nintendo-ds/</guid><description>Introduction A few months ago, I stumbled upon the DS Linux project while browsing the internet. The project is not actively developed anymore (which was to expect as the DS is a pretty old device with the first model released in 2004). However, working builds are available on their website here and I wanted to play a bit with it.
Installation According to the project’s website, DS Linux is compatible with the original DS and the DS Lite (this is the one that I own), and maybe the newer models in compatibility mode.</description></item><item><title>Wake on Lan and Dual Boot</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2020/10/06/wake-on-lan-and-dual-boot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2020/10/06/wake-on-lan-and-dual-boot/</guid><description>Introduction Wake on Lan is a technology delvelopped in 1995, that allows you to start a computer by sending a magic packet (usually in udp). I use it since a few years and it is especially useful when you are in a remote place, you can just start your computer and connect to it through rdp. The only problem is that this approach is not really suitable for dual-boot setups.</description></item><item><title>Use your oculus rift completly offline</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2020/10/04/use-your-oculus-rift-completly-offline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2020/10/04/use-your-oculus-rift-completly-offline/</guid><description>Introduction With the recent turn of events (upcoming requirement of a facebook account to use your oculus), I finally decided to get my oculus working fully offline, but it was harder than I thought.
First Attempt Indeed, if you can use your headset without an internet connection, you still need to have the oculus software installed. So, after some research, I came across this topic where a user describes how to backup the installer files to use it offline.</description></item></channel></rss>