<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>python - Tag - DrosoCode</title><link>https://thomasz.me/tags/python/</link><description>python - Tag - DrosoCode</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>contact@thomasz.me (droso)</managingEditor><webMaster>contact@thomasz.me (droso)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomasz.me/tags/python/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A comparison of upscaling software in 2021</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/a-comparison-of-upscaling-software-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>droso</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2022/01/14/a-comparison-of-upscaling-software-in-2021/</guid><description>A few months ago, I started to search for some upscaling software to integrate into Zogwine, my media center with the goal of upscaling some of my old animes either on the fly or via some kind of preprocessing. I found quite a lot of projects on github, and especially the Video2X project which gathered many different projects and versions. So I decided to do a quick benchmark to decide which one to use.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading your RGB with WLED, Aurora and OpenRGB</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2021/11/29/upgrading-your-rgb-with-wled-aurora-and-openrgb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>droso</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2021/11/29/upgrading-your-rgb-with-wled-aurora-and-openrgb/</guid><description>I was always interested in going furether than the pre-made RGB equipement by various manufacturers because each system was only compatible with only one brand (ex: iCUE, RGB Fusion, Asus RGB …) and that their RGB softwares were very unfinished and didn’t exploit the full potential of the RGB hardware.
First Attempt So, when I built my first desktop PC, I decided to create from scratch a custom RGB system. This was based on an arduino board, internally connected to my PC using USB.</description></item><item><title>Control your lights with a Nintendo DS</title><link>https://thomasz.me/2020/11/03/control-your-light-with-a-nintendo-ds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>droso</author><guid>https://thomasz.me/2020/11/03/control-your-light-with-a-nintendo-ds/</guid><description>Introduction A few months ago, I stumbled upon the DS Linux project while browsing the internet. The project is not actively developed anymore (which was to expect as the DS is a pretty old device with the first model released in 2004). However, working builds are available on their website here and I wanted to play a bit with it.
Installation According to the project’s website, DS Linux is compatible with the original DS and the DS Lite (this is the one that I own), and maybe the newer models in compatibility mode.</description></item></channel></rss>